Futurama presents...
Brought to you by
Mutual of Omicron.
Insuring your world,
and its destruction.
Tonight's planet,
a primitive backwater known only as...
Earth.
Of all
the creatures on Earth,
none has a more thrilling life cycle
than the intrepid salmon.
It all begins in a cold,
freshwater stream,
where the salmon
eggs incubate.
I'm born, baby!
The new hatchlings
are known as "fry."
What's your name?
I don't have a name.
I'm a salmon.
After three years
in the stream,
the young salmon are ready
for the arduous journey to the ocean.
I do look forward to
cavorting in the spray.
The trip will be dangerous.
Only three in 10 will survive.
Let's all 10 of
us go together.
There's safety in numbers.
Mm. I reckon my boy
will be right pleased
when I regurgitate
that into his mouth.
Looming ahead, nature's waterfall,
the cliff of the waters.
Ah.
It sure is relaxing
getting swept along by this current.
Whoa!
Oh, my!
Oh, dear!
Oh, yes!
This just in.
Three dead in foamy plunge.
Still, six out of 10 alive.
That's considered good for our species!
Five out of 10, also nice.
Yep.
And so the salmon
reach the ocean, birthplace of all life.
Except the salmon.
Hello. Who are you?
I'm a salmon.
Really? Me, too!
No way!
So, hey, I don't
want to be too forward,
but I'd like to mate with you in a few
years when we're sexually mature.
I'd like that.
Oh!
What have we here?
I'm a Pisces. And you?
Also Pisces.
We're all Pisces.
Then it's a date.
I'll see you at spawning time.
No, thanks.
I've already found my mate.
You haven't
ignored the last of me.
Having reached maturity,
it is time for the salmon to spawn.
Thus begins their
1000-mile journey
back to the exact stream
in which they were born.
So how do we
find our way home?
Nobody knows!
Experts are unsure whether
salmon navigate by memory,
sense of smell, or by detecting
variations in Earth's magnetic field.
Okay, everybody do
one of those three things.
Well, this is it.
Home, stream home.
No, it isn't!
I was born in the next stream up.
You're from
Next Stream Up? So am I!
I can tell by
the magnets in my head, or whatever.
Let's go!
The urge to spawn
drives the salmon
inexorably toward
the stream of its birth.
Stupid body! Why won't you go
to that other stream?
Nobody knows!
I just told you!
Goodbye! It was fun
maturing with you,
but at this point
in my life cycle,
I need a mate who's
within squirting distance.
I'll never forget you, fish.
Come on, loxy lady, it's time for
us to get naughty by nature!
No!
Well, here goes something...
Don't make it...
Don't make it!
Ouch.
Son of a fish!
Jumping is for suckers.
I'm good!
Who wants a piece of me?
I'll try a bite!
Having completed
its perilous journey,
the exhausted salmon
enters the final phase of its life cycle.
The female deposits her eggs
and the male fertilizes them.
Okay, who's next?
There's a lot more
where that came from!
I can't see them anymore!
What if they're mating?
Who cares?
Just release your milt already!
Everybody's doing it!
No! I refuse
to release anything
unless it's in the vicinity of the eggs
of the fish I love!
Tell my offspring I
loved me very much...
Oh, yeah.
Plop those roundies.
All right, step aside.
Time to let my bad boys loose.
I am Brrr,
devourer of fish and honey!
I'm coming, darling!
I shouldn't,
but who's counting?
Help! Fish police!
Two salmon for dinner?
What? It's spawning season!
It's a bear holiday!
That is what you said
when you found those Boy Scouts!
Next you'll be telling me
I can't crap in the woods!
That's it!
We're hibernating
in separate caves this winter!
My love!
You made it!
You overcame salmon instinct
and left your home stream for me!
So are you gonna
fertilize my eggs now?
Already taken care of.
Well, we swam away
and then we came back.
It's been
an interesting life.
And the best part is,
it had a happy ending.
And so the endless
circle of life comes to an end,
meaningless and grim.
Why did they live,
and why did they die?
No reason.
The isolated
Galapagos Islands.
A veritable pageant
of evolutionary science.
Home to dozens of species
found nowhere else,
such as Darwin's finches
and the marine iguana.
Also the blue-footed booby!
That's fairly interesting!
Note the blue coloration of the...
Of all the creatures
in the Galapagos,
none is rarer or more tragic
than the Pinta Island tortoise.
Only a single living specimen
is known to exist,
Lonesome Hubert.
Sad news, everyone.
I'm lonesome.
Hey, would it cheer you up if we gave you
a symbiotic parasite cleaning?
Would it? Would it?
Would it?
Fine, knock yourself out.
The Galapagos finches
eat parasites off the tortoise's skin,
a mutually
beneficial arrangement.
Except for the parasite!
How's that, Hubert?
Feeling better?
A good beaking usually cheers me right
up, but today it's no use.
My species is as
good as extinct.
I haven't seen
a female of my kind in over 100 years!
There's got to be a lady tortoise
out there for you, Hubert.
What about her?
Hey, good lookin',
I've got a lichen that needs a lickin'.
Are you crazy?
She's a slightly different subspecies!
See how her shell
flares imperceptibly at the neck?
Talk about
a cloaca shrinker.
Well, haven't you
ever met a girl tortoise
who had that whole
"same subspecies" thing going on?
Oh my, yes. When I was
a young tortoise of 50,
I met a hot young
piece of shell
by a Palo Santo tree on
the far side of the island.
Let's go look for her!
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon!
I've always wondered
if she's still there, waiting for me.
But the trip is far too long.
It's only 100 feet!
At my age, it might as well be 200
feet. I'd never make it!
- Come on, you can make it!
- You can do it!
Well, let me think it over.
Let's go already!
Watch out!
What brings yous to
this part of the isles?
He's gonna eat us!
Don't be such a finch.
We Galapagos tortoises
have no natural predators.
That's so fascinating!
I never thought I'd live
to see this tree again.
Thank you for
staying with me, Fry.
I'm not Fry.
I'm his great-great-grandson, Fry.
- You are?
- My beak is different, see?
It evolved a slightly bigger hook
over the generations
to help me eat the cactus
on this part of the island.
Watch!
I'm stuck!
Oops.
So where's your
lady tortoise, Hubert?
Lady what?
Wait, there she is!
After all these years,
I've found her!
Oh, my darling!
You haven't aged a day!
Should we say something?
Nah. Let him have his fun.
All right.
Let's just do what comes naturally.
I'll get things started
with a little neck extension...
Then a couple
of these...
And here we go!
What the tropical
hell are you doing?
What?
I've been saving myself for 100 years,
and this is how you repay me?
Who is that
hard-shelled skank? I'll kill her!
Wait, I can explain...
Shut up!
I'm going to crack that hussy
open like a slutty Brazil nut!
This volcanic archipelago
isn't big enough for the both of us.
Yeah, you'd better topple.
You always were
a hot-blooded Latina.
Like all reptiles,
the Galapagos tortoise is cold-blooded.
Okay, neck, tap, tap,
climb, climb,
and we're back in business.
Should we be watching this?
It seems kind of personal.
That's not an issue for us.
We're wildlife.
What about the moaning?
Is it okay to listen?
Sure, but act like
it's no big deal.
Just pretend
you're eating seeds.
Is it weird if I talk about
his crazy turtle penis?
No.
Well, okay then.
Yes, it's been lovely.
Hang on a second.
The Galapagos tortoise lays
a clutch of between six and 15 eggs.
What do you want?
I'm 150 years old.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait!
Aren't you going
to watch over your young?
Tortoises don't do that, do we?
I sure as hell don't.
Anyway, I've done my part.
The species is saved!
And so, the survival of
the Pinta Island tortoise is assured.
Mama!
And so, the extinction
of the Pinta Island tortoise is assured.
Two hundred million years
of evolution, snuffed out.
For, in the end, nature is horrific,
and teaches us nothing.
Coming up next,
the hilarious antics of the elephant seal,
the clown of the sea.
Of all
the spectacles in nature,
few can match
the mating ritual of the elephant seal.
Certainly not the salmon.
And the tortoise? Yeah, right.
The huge, lumbering males
defend patches of beach
to deny their rivals access
to the breeding grounds.
Just as in human society,
only the biggest, most obnoxious
males have any chance of mating.
Aw, yeah!
Survival of the fattest!
The dominant male,
or "beachmaster,"
maintains a harem
of up to 50 females.
Okay, harem, let's get to it.
Form an orderly heap on top of me.
I like mating with
Beachmaster 'cause he's the largest.
While the Beachmaster enjoys
the spoils of victory...
Whoo! I'm doin' it
in my sleep!
The lesser males languish
at the edge of the colony,
unable to attract their own
harem due to age...
Harem?
I can barely see 'em!
Immaturity...
I'm scared.
Or other reasons.
Hmm. I don't know, does this kelp
scarf make me look fat enough?
It's so unfair.
That bloated Casanova gets all the ladies!
Even that one with
the exquisite fat rolls.
Back off, losers!
Stay away from my beaches!
You big bully!
Bite my freshly molted,
blubber-filled ass.
You're just
a giant lump of fat!
Do you even have
an ass under there?
I'm 40% ass!
Arf, arf!
Now beat it!
Boo!
With no hope
of defeating the Beachmaster,
some so-called "sneaky" males
adopt a risky strategy,
attempting to mate
with one of his harem
while he is
asleep or distracted.
So, any of you guys thinking of
being a sneaky male this season?
This season?
Walrus don't
need no chicanery.
Once a lady goes walrus,
she never... She...
No one ever goes walrus.
I'm a little old for it now,
but in my prime, I was quite the sneaker.
How did you do it?
Well, while the Beachmaster
was off behind a whale carcass,
loudly fornicating
with my beloved mother,
I snuck past and surprised my
sweetie with a romantic meal.
A romantic meal?
The search for food
takes the elephant seal
to depths few other
mammals can reach.
In this pitch-black abyss,
life takes on bizarre and horrific forms.
So, welcome to the abyss.
Road trip!
Kill all penguins...
Kill all penguins.
What's the matter with you?
You just crushed seven of our babies!
Yeah, we can
always make more.
Come on, floozies,
let's repopulate!
With the Beachmaster occupied,
the sneaky male makes his move.
I can't believe you came!
The Beachmaster'll kill you
if he finds out!
Also, who are you?
I'm in love with you!
And I don't care what he thinks.
Here, I brought you
something.
Hurray! We're three friends at the beach!
Wait, what's happening, friend?
The female conveys her
receptivity through subtle vocalizations.
Wanna do it?
So soon? Oh, well...
- Sneaky male, eh?
- I thought I told you...
Oh, my!
- Well, nice try.
- Better luck next season.
- You gave it a shot!
- Pathetic.
Sorry you didn't
get to mate.
But, hey, we can still
play some beach games.
Who's up for some Twister?
No! We beta males
deserve better.
When we're in charge,
we'll treat females with respect,
keeping sensible harems
of no more than five.
And it begins with me.
Sir, I challenge you
to a duel for control of the beach!
Aw...
Hang on...
Okay, let's fight.
That's it.
No more Mr. Nice-Jerk.
The battle
will rage for hours,
until both males
are exhausted or dead.
Beachmaster, stop fighting!
He's been dead since yesterday!
What? He's dead?
Whoo! I'm killin' dudes
in my sleep! Yo! Clean up!
And so, with the threat to the
Beachmaster's supremacy eliminated,
order is restored
for another year.
Another year, another generation of
pups fathered by me, Beachmaster.
I'm the greatest, baby!
You go, Beachmaster!
And so concludes
our exploration of planet Earth.
For a holographic
brain injection of tonight's program,
send $5 to this station,
care of me, the narrator.
Good night.
Mutual of Omicron.
Have you insured your planet?